<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>

<!-- test -->

<Module xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1" name="PP-Module for Wireless LAN Clients"
    xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <!-- <inline-comment color='green'> Hello World QQQQ </inline-comment> -->
  <!-- <inline-comment color='blue' linebreak='yes'> Hello World QQQQ </inline-comment> -->
  <PPReference title="PP Reference">
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>PP-Module for Wireless LAN Clients</PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>1.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2019-08-28</PPPubDate>
      <PPCertificationID>unassigned</PPCertificationID>
      <CCVersion>3.1R5</CCVersion>
      <Keywords>WLAN; Wireless LAN; Wireless Networking; 802.11</Keywords>
      <entry>
        <name>Registration</name>
        <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
      </entry>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>

  <RevisionHistory role="final">
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date>2019-08-28</date>
      <subject>Initial Release</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>

  <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
    <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview">
      
      The scope of the Wireless LAN (WLAN) Client <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> is to describe the security functionality of a Wireless Local Area Network (LAN) Client in terms of [<abbr linkend="CC"/>] 
      and to define functional and assurance requirements for such products. This <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> is intended for use with the following <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>s: <h:ul>
        <h:li>General Purpose Operating System (GPOS) Protection Profile, Version 4.2.1</h:li>
        <h:li>Mobile Device Fundamentals (MDF) Protection Profile, Version 3.1</h:li>
      </h:ul>
      <h:p/> These <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>s are valid because a WLAN Client is
      a part of either a commercial operating system that can be installed on a general-purpose computer or an operating system that runs on a purpose-built mobile device.
      
    </section>
    <section title="Terms" id="glossary"> The following sections provide both Common Criteria and
      technology terms used in this document. 
              <subsection title="Common Criteria Terms">
            <glossary>
              <entry>
                <term><abbr title="Base Protection Profile">Base-PP</abbr></term>
                <description>Protection Profile used to build a PP-Configuration.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term><abbr title="Common Criteria">CC</abbr></term>
                <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation
                  (International Standard ISO/IEC 15408).</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term>Common Criteria Testing Laboratory</term>
                <description>Within the context of the Common Criteria Evaluation and Validation Scheme
                  (CCEVS), an IT security evaluation facility, accredited by the National Voluntary
                  Laboratory Accreditation Program (NVLAP) and approved by the NIAP Validation Body to
                  conduct Common Criteria-based evaluations.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term><abbr title="Common Evaluation Methodology">CEM</abbr></term>
                <description>Common Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security
                  Evaluation.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term><abbr title="Protection Profile">PP</abbr></term>
                <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category
                  of products.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term><abbr title="Protection Profile Configuration">PP-Configuration</abbr></term>
                <description>A comprehensive set of security requirements for a product type that consists of at least one Base-PP and at least one PP-Module.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term><abbr title="Protection Profile Module">PP-Module</abbr></term>
                <description>An implementation-independent statement of security needs for a TOE type
                  complementary to one or more Base Protection Profiles. </description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term><abbr title="Security Functional Requirement">SFR</abbr></term>
                <description>A requirement for security enforcement by the <abbr linkend="TOE"
                />.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term><abbr title="Security Target">ST</abbr></term>
                <description>A set of implementation-dependent security requirements for a specific
                  product.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term><abbr title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</abbr></term>
                <description>The product under evaluation.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term><abbr title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</abbr></term>
                <description>The security functionality of the product under evaluation.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term><abbr title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</abbr></term>
                <description>A description of how a <abbr linkend="TOE"/> satisfies the <abbr
                  linkend="SFR"/>s in an <abbr linkend="ST"/>.</description>
              </entry>
            </glossary>
          </subsection>
          <subsection title="Technical Terms">
            <glossary>
              <entry>
                <term>Access Point</term>
                <description>A device that provides the network interface that enables wireless client hosts to access a wired network.
                  Once authenticated as trusted nodes on the wired infrastructure, the APs provide the encryption service on
                  the wireless network between the wireless client and the RF interface of the AP.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                 <term>Administrator</term>
                 <description>A user that has administrative privilege to configure the TOE.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term>Authentication Server</term>
                <description>A server on the wired network that receives authentication credentials from wireless clients and determines their validity.</description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term>Authentication Credentials</term>
                <description>The information the system uses to verify that the user or administrator is
                  authorized to access the TOE or network. Credentials can exist in various forms, such as username/password or digital 
                  certificates.</description>
              </entry>              
              <entry>
                <term>Critical Security Parameter</term>
                <description>Security related information, e.g. secret and private cryptographic keys,
                  and authentication data such as passwords and PINs, whose disclosure or modification can compromise the
                  security of a cryptographic module.</description>
              </entry> 
              <entry>
                <term>Entropy Source</term>
                <description>A cryptographic function that provides a seed for a random number generator by accumulating
                  the outputs from one or more noise sources. The functionality includes a measure of the minimum work
                  required to guess a given output and tests to ensure that the noise sources are operating properly.
              </description>
              </entry>               
              <entry>
                <term>Extensible Authentication Protocol</term>
                <description>An authentication framework, used in wireless networks, that uses PKI to authenticate both the authentication server and the wireless client.
                </description>
              </entry>  
              <entry>
                <term>FIPS-Approved Cryptographic Function</term>
                <description>A cryptographic operation that is specified for use by FIPS 140.
                </description>
              </entry>               
              <entry>
                <term>IEEE 802.1X</term>
                <description>A standard for port-based network access control that defines an authentication mechanism for WLAN Clients to attach to a wired network.
                </description>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                <term>Unauthorized User</term>
                <description>A user that has not been granted the ability to use the TOE.
                </description>
              </entry>

            </glossary>
      </subsection>
	  </section>
    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription">
     
     This document specifies Security Functional Requirements for a WLAN Client. The TOE defined
     by this <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> is the WLAN Client, a component executing on a client machine (often referred to as
     a "remote access client"). The TOE establishes a secure wireless tunnel between the client
     device and a WLAN Access System through which all data will traverse.
     <h:p/>
      A WLAN Client allows remote users to use client machines to establish wireless communication
      with a private network through a WLAN Access System. IP packets passing between the
      private network and a WLAN Client are encrypted. The WLAN Client protects the
      data between itself and the private network, protection the confidentiality and integrity 
      of data in transit, even though it traverses a wireless connection.
      The focus of the Security Functional Requirements in this <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> is on the following fundamental
      aspects of a WLAN Client:
      <h:ul>
        <h:li>Authentication of the WLAN Client;</h:li>
        <h:li>Authentication of the Authentication Servert;</h:li>
        <h:li>Cryptographic protection of data in transit; and</h:li>
        
        <!-- SME: don't know what specifically this refers to, unsure if we should keep as-is, change somehow, or remove altogether -->
        <h:li>Implementation of services.</h:li>
        
      </h:ul>
      The WLAN Client establishes an 802.11 tunnel between the client device and the network
      infrastructure using IEEE 802.1X with EAP-TLS for authentication. It performs mutual
      authentication to an AS in the private network as part of the EAP-TLS exchange. The EAP-TLS
      exchange uses certificates for mutual authentication. The WLAN Client examines the machine
      certificate transmitted from the AS, checks its validity, and ensures the certificate is signed by a
      trusted Certificate Authority (CA). The AS will authenticate the WLAN Client certificate at the
      same time. When the EAP-TLS exchange completes successfully, the network allows the WLAN
      Client to finish establishing a secure communication tunnel to the private network. The WLAN
      Client sets up an encrypted, authenticated channel to the WLAN Access System using a 4 way
      handshake, as specified in IEEE 802.11. Once the channel is established, all communication
      between the WLAN Client to the WLAN Access System is encrypted with AES in CCMP mode and
      optionally AES is GCMP mode, as specified in <cite linkend="bib80211"/>.
      
      <subsection title="TOE Boundary" id="TOEboundary">
        The WLAN Client (Figure 1), as defined by this <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/>, is a component executing on a remote access
        client machine. Note the client is depicted as just a small portion of the WLAN client "machine."
        As such, the TOE must rely heavily on the TOE’s operational environment (host platform,
        network stack, and operating system) for its execution domain and its proper usage. The TOE
        will rely on the IT environment to address much of the security functionality related to
        administrative functions.  
        
        <figure entity="images/Toe.png" title="WLAN Client Operating Environment" id="toe"/>
      </subsection>
      <!-- 
      <subsection title="TOE Platform" id="TOEplatform">
      </subsection>  -->
    </section>
    
    <!-- SME: the old WLAN EP did not define use cases, these have been added. Will need review. -->
    <section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">Requirements in this PP-Module are designed to
      address the security problems in at least the following use cases. These use cases are intentionally
      very broad, as many specific use cases exist within these larger categories.
      
      <usecases>
                <usecase title="General-Purpose Operating System" id="gpos">
          <description>
            This use case is for a WLAN Client TOE that is part of a general-purpose operating system. Specifically, the WLAN Client TOE is expected to be part of the operating system itself and not a standalone third-party application that 
            is installed on top of it.
          </description>
        </usecase>
        <usecase title="Mobile Device" id="md">
          <description>
            This use case is for a WLAN Client TOE that is part of a mobile operating system that runs on a mobile device. Specifically, the WLAN Client TOE is expected to be part of the mobile operating system itself and not 
            a standalone third-party application that is acquired from the mobile vendor's application store.
          </description>
        </usecase>
        
        <!-- to do: add use case for administrative capabilities if one needs to exist (currently TBD) -->
        
      </usecases>
    </section>
  </chapter>


  <chapter title="Conformance Claims" id="conf">
    <cclaims>
      <cclaim title="Conformance Statement">
        <description> This <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> inherits exact conformance as required from
          the specified <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> and as defined in the <abbr linkend="CC"/> and
          <abbr linkend="CEM"/> addenda for Exact Conformance, Selection-Based SFRs, and Optional
          SFRs (dated May 2017).<h:p/> 
          The following PPs and PP-Modules are allowed to
          be specified in a PP-Configuration with this PP-Module. <h:ul>
            <h:li>PP-Module for VPN Client, Version 2.1</h:li>
          </h:ul>
        </description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim title="CC Conformance Claims">
        <description>This <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> is conformant to Parts 2 (extended) and 3
          (conformant) of Common Criteria Version 3.1, Release 5 [<abbr linkend="CC"/>].
        </description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim title="Package Claims">
        <description>There are no package claims for this PP-Module.</description>
      </cclaim>
    </cclaims>
  </chapter>


  <chapter id="spd" title="Security Problem Description">
    This PP-Module is written to address the situation when an entity desires wireless access to a private
    network. To allow access to the private network, the entity (machine) must be authenticated
    before a secure communications channel can be established. The TOE is the entity that seeks to
    be authenticated and be given access to services offered by the protected network and is the
    Supplicant in the IEEE 802.1X framework.
    
    <section id="threats" title="Threats"> The following threats are specific to WLAN Clients, and represent an addition to those identified in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>s. 
      <!-- Note: Threats contained in both base-PPs should not be listed in the PP-Module (section 3.1 or 6), but objectives can still be mapped to them (section 4.3). 
        For these threats do not include a <description> or <consistency-rationale> section. If a <description> section is included then the threat is listed in Section 3.1. 
        If no description is listed, then threat is only listed in section 4.3 (not in 3.1 or 6) -->
      <threats>
        <threat id="T.TSF_FAILURE">
          <description>Security mechanisms of the TOE generally build up from a primitive set of mechanisms (e.g.,
            memory management, privileged modes of process execution) to more complex sets of
            mechanisms. Failure of the primitive mechanisms could lead to a compromise in more complex
            mechanisms, resulting in a compromise of the TSF.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.TSF_SELF_TEST">
          <rationale>TBD</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        
        <threat id="T.UNAUTHORIZED_ACCESS">
          <description>A user may gain unauthorized access to the TOE data and TOE executable code. A malicious
            user, process, or external IT entity may masquerade as an authorized entity in order to gain
            unauthorized access to data or TOE resources. A malicious user, process, or external IT entity
            may misrepresent itself as the TOE to obtain identification and authentication data.</description>
                <objective-refer ref="O.AUTH_COMM">
          <rationale>TBD</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
        <objective-refer ref="O.CRYPTOGRAPHIC_FUNCTIONS">
          <rationale>TBD</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
        <objective-refer ref="O.TOE_ADMINISTRATION">
          <rationale>TBD</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
        <objective-refer ref="O.WIRELESS_ACCESS_POINT_CONNECTION">
          <rationale>TBD</rationale>
        </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        
        <threat id="T.UNDETECTED_ACTIONS">
          <description>Malicious remote users or external IT entities may take actions that adversely affect the
            security of the TOE. These actions may remain undetected and thus their effects cannot be
            effectively mitigated.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.SYSTEM_MONITORING">
            <rationale>TBD</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
      </threats>
     </section>
        
    <section id="Assumptions" title="Assumptions">
      <assumptions>
        <assumption id="A.NO_TOE_BYPASS">
          <description>Information cannot flow between the wireless client and the internal wired
            network without passing through the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.NO_TOE_BYPASS">
            <rationale>TBD</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
        <assumption id="A.TRUSTED_ADMIN">
          <description><abbr linkend="TOE"/> Administrators are trusted to follow and apply all administrator guidance in
            a trusted manner.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.TRUSTED_ADMIN">
            <rationale>TBD</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
      </assumptions>
    </section>
    
    <section id="securityPolicy" title="Organizational Security Policies">
      No organizational policies have been identified that are specific to WLAN Clients. However, any
      organizational security policies defined in the Base-PPs will also apply to WLAN Clients.
    </section>
  </chapter>


  <chapter title="Security Objectives" id="obj">
    <section title="Security Objectives for the TOE" id="SecurityObjectivesTOE">
      <SOs>
        <SO id="O.AUTH_COMM">
          <description>The <abbr linkend="TOE"/> will provide a means to ensure that it is
            communicating with an authorized Access Point and
            not some other entity pretending to be an authorized
            Access Point, and will provide assurance to the Access
            Point of its identity.</description>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_TLSC_EXT.1/WLAN"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_TLSC_EXT.2/WLAN (selection-based)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_PAE_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.2/WLAN"/>
          <component-refer ref="FTP_ITC_EXT.1/WLAN"/>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.CRYPTOGRAPHIC_FUNCTIONS">
          <description>The <abbr linkend="TOE"/> will provide or use cryptographic functions
            (i.e., encryption/decryption and digital signature
            operations) to maintain the confidentiality and allow
            for detection of modification of data that are
            transmitted outside the <abbr linkend="TOE"/> and its host
            environment.</description>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM.1/WLAN"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM.2/WLAN"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.3 (if GPOS is Base-PP)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.4 (if MDF is Base-PP)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(1) (from either Base-PP)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(2) (from either Base-PP)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(3) (from either Base-PP)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(4) (from either Base-PP)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_RBG_EXT.1 (from either Base-PP)"/>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.SYSTEM_MONITORING">
          <description>The <abbr linkend="TOE"/> will provide the capability to generate audit
            data.</description>
          <component-refer ref="FAU_GEN.1/WLAN"/>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.TOE_ADMINISTRATION">
          <description>The <abbr linkend="TOE"/> will provide mechanisms to allow
            administrators to be able to configure the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>. </description>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.4 (optional)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FMT_SMF.1/WLAN"/>
        </SO>
        <SO id="T.SELF_TEST">
          <description>The <abbr linkend="TOE"/> will provide the capability to test some
            subset of its security functionality to ensure it is operating properly. </description>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_TST_EXT.1/WLAN"/>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.WIRELESS_ACCESS_POINT_CONNECTION">
          <description>The <abbr linkend="TOE"/> will provide the capability to restrict the
            wireless access points to which it will connect.</description>
          <component-refer ref="FTA_WSE_EXT.1"/>
        </SO>
      </SOs>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Security Objectives for the Operational Environment"
      id="SecurityObjectivesTOEorEnvironment"><!-- The Operational Environment of the TOE implements technical and procedural measures 
      to assist the TOE in correctly providing its security functionality (which is defined by the security objectives for the TOE). 
      The security objectives for the Operational Environment consist of a set of statements describing the goals that the Operational Environment should achieve. 
      This section defines the security objectives that are to be addressed by the IT domain or by non-technical or procedural means. 
      The assumptions identified in Section 3 are incorporated as security objectives for the environment. --><SOEs>
        <SOE id="OE.NO_TOE_BYPASS">
          <description>Information cannot flow between external and internal networks located
            in different enclaves without passing through the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.</description>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.TRUSTED_ADMIN">
          <description><abbr linkend="TOE"/> administrators are trusted to follow and apply all administrator
            guidance in a trusted manner.</description>
        </SOE>
      </SOEs>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Security Objectives Rationale" id="SOR">This section describes how the
      assumptions, threats, and organizational security policies map to the security objectives.
      <InsertSPDCorrespondence/></section>
  </chapter>
  
  <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">
    <!-- SME: the intro to this chapter appears to be getting populated with default text rather than what is specified here, which is problematic because the default text does not
    define refinements correctly for this Module. How can we get it to use what is here instead of the default? -->
    This chapter describes the security requirements
    which have to be fulfilled by the <abbr linkend="OS"/>. Those requirements comprise functional
    components from Part 2 and assurance components from Part 3 of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>. 
        
    The following notations are used: <h:ul>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Refinement</h:b> operation (denoted by <h:b>bold text</h:b>): Is used to add details to a
        requirement, and thus further restricts a requirement.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Selection</h:b> operation (denoted by <h:i>italicized text</h:i>): Is used to select one or more options
        provided by the [CC] in stating a requirement.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Assignment</h:b> operation (denoted by <h:span class="assignable-content">italicized text</h:span>): Is used to assign a
        specific value to an unspecified parameter, such as the length of a password.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Iteration</h:b> operation: Identified with a slash followed by a unique text string (e.g. "/WLAN") or a number inside parentheses (e.g. "(1)")</h:li>
    </h:ul>

    
        <base-pp version="4.2.1" name="General Purpose Operating Systems" product="Operating System" short="GPOS"
          url="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=442&amp;id=442">
<!--       xmlurl="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/commoncriteria/mobile-device/master/input/mobile-device.xml"> -->


      <modified-sfrs>
        <subsection id="fcs" title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)">
          <f-component id="fcs_ckm_ext.3" name="Cryptographic Key Destruction">

            <note role="application"> This SFR exists in the GPOS PP and does not need to be modified for this PP-Module. Note
              however that its scope is expanded to include keys and key material that are used by the TSF
              described by this PP-Module. This SFR has not been iterated because it is assumed that the key
              destruction function is at least partially implemented by the underlying platform as opposed to
              the WLAN Client itself. For the purposes of this requirement, it is sufficient for the TOE to invoke
              the correct underlying functions of the host to perform the zeroization—it does not imply that
              the TOE has to include a kernel-mode memory driver to ensure the data are zeroized.
              <h:p/>
              Any security related information (such as keys, authentication data, and passwords) must be
              zeroized when no longer in use to prevent the disclosure or modification of security critical data.
              <h:p/>
              The zeroization indicated above applies to each intermediate storage area for plaintext key or CSP
              (i.e., any storage, such as memory buffers, that is included in the path of such data) upon the
              transfer of the key or CSP to another location.
              <h:p/>
              Additionally, although IEEE 802.11-2016 does not specify PMK lifetimes (described in IEEE
              802.11-2016 Section 11.6.1.3) for WLAN Clients, these lifetimes should be limited, and the
              PMKSA cleared, in such a way as to prevent continued use of the same PMK for more than 24
              hours. Thus, for PMKs, “when no longer needed” is after 24 hours.
            </note>
          </f-component>
          
          
          <f-component id="fcs_cop.1" name="Cryptographic Operation">
            <note role="application">Several iterations of this SFR exist in the GPOS PP and do not need to be
              modified for this PP-Module. Note however that their scope is expanded to include cryptographic
              operations that are required by the WLAN Client in order to perform its security functionality.
            </note>
          </f-component>
          
          <f-component id="fcs_rbg_ext.1" name="Random Bit Generation">
            
            <note role="application">This SFR exists in the GPOS PP and does not need to be modified for this PP-Module. Note
              however that its scope is expanded to include random bit generation functions that are required
              by the WLAN Client in order to perform its security functionality.
            </note>
          </f-component>

          
        </subsection>
      </modified-sfrs>
      <additional-sfrs/>
      
          
          <!-- 
      <con-toe> When this <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> is used to extend the MDF PP, the TOE type for
        the overall TOE is still a mobile device. The TOE boundary is simply extended to include the
          <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent application that runs on the mobile device.</con-toe>
      <con-sec-prob/>
      <con-obj/>
      <con-op-en/>
      <con-mod id="T.BACKUP"> This threat protects user data from unauthorized logical access. An
        attacker would attempt to exploit this threat by first exploiting the T.PHYSICAL, T.FLAWAPP,
        or T.PERSISTENT threats defined in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> against the mobile device
        as a whole, and then using the device itself as an attack vector against any backup data
        stored on the TOE.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="O.ACCOUNTABILITY"> The <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> provides an objective,
        O.INTEGRITY, that ensures that the integrity of the mobile device is maintained. This
        objective assists in the implementation of O.INTEGRITY by providing records of
        administrative activity, which would include actions that could cause the integrity of the
        mobile device to be lost.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="O.APPLY_POLICY"> This objective supports the implementation of the O.CONFIG
        objective defined in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> by specifying an additional method by
        which the TSF may be configured.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="O.DATA_PROTECTION_TRANSIT"> This objective extends the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"
        />’s O.COMMS objective by ensuring that the communications related to <abbr linkend="MDM"/>
        Agent functionality are secured in the same manner as other sensitive data transmitted
        to/from the mobile device.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="O.STORAGE"> This objective extends the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>’s O.STORAGE
        objective by ensuring that the mobile device’s data-at-rest protection mechanisms can also
        be used to secure the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent and related data.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="OE.DATA_PROPER_ADMIN"> This objective extends the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>’s
        OE.CONFIG objective by expecting that TOE administrators act appropriately when installing
        or configuring the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="OE.DATA_PROPER_USER"> This objective extends the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>’s
        OE.NOTIFY and OE.PRECAUTION objectives by setting reasonable expectations for user security
        behavior.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="OE.IT_ENTERPRISE"> This objective helps mitigate the T.EAVESDROP and T.NETWORK
        threats defined by the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> by reducing the network exposure of the
        mobile device. This does not conflict with the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> because the <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/> does not set specific expectations for the level of security that the
        enterprise provides, but all use cases from the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> set expectations
        that the mobile device is used for some enterprise purposes so it is reasonable to expect
        the enterprise have security controls in place to protect these functions. </con-mod>
      <con-mod id="OE.MOBILE_DEVICE_PLATFORM"> This objective is suitable because the <abbr
          linkend="MDM"/> Agent can reasonably expect the device it has been deployed on to be
        secure.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="OE.WIRELESS_NETWORK"> This objective is suitable because while the <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/> does not associate any availability metrics with wireless
        communications, the mobile device will always provide the ability to access a wireless
        network.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fau_alt_ext.2"> This SFR requires the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent to use a
        trusted channel defined by FTP_ITC_EXT.1 in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> to transmit data
        about its own behavior to the Operational Environment.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fau_gen.1(2)"> The <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> defines FAU_GEN.1; this <abbr
          linkend="PP-Module"/> defines a second iteration to use the same audit mechanism to
        generate audit records for the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent’s behavior. It may alternatively
        allow the TSF to generate its own audit trail, which does not impede the MDF from enforcing
        its own security functionality.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fau_sel.1(2)"> The <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> defines FAU_SEL.1; this <abbr
          linkend="PP-Module"/> defines a second iteration to use the same audit mechanism to select
        the auditable events to be generated by the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent. Note that the <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/> does not mandate this requirement so it is possible that only the
          <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent portion of the TOE may implement it. In this case, the SFR
        provides a selection for the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent to implement its own mechanism to
        perform this function rather than a platform-provided one.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fia_enr_ext.2"> This SFR requires the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent to record data
        that it receives from the Operational Environment. It does not need to use any functionality
        defined in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> to do this, and doing this does not prevent the
        enforcement of any security requirements from the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>. </con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fmt_pol_ext.2"> This SFR requires the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent to use a
        digital signature algorithm to validate data that it receives from the Operational
        Environment. To do this, the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent will use the functionality defined
        by the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> in FCS_COP.1(3).</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fmt_smf_ext.4"> This SFR defines the ability of the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent
        to interact with the mobile device to execute the management functions defined by
        FMT_MOF_EXT.1 in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>. The <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> specifically
        indicates in FMT_MOF_EXT.1.2 that some management functions may be performed via
        MDM.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fmt_unr_ext.1"> This SFR defines the functions performed by the <abbr
          linkend="MDM"/> Agent when unenrolled from an <abbr linkend="MDM"/>. The <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/> defines unenrollment actions in FMT_SMF_EXT.2, and goes on to note
        that these actions may be performed “perhaps via an <abbr linkend="MDM"/> agent,” so this is
        expected behavior. </con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fau_stg_ext.3"> This SFR defines the ability of the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent
        to store generated audit data in the audit storage provided by the mobile device. The <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/> defines the capability for audit storage in FAU_STG.1.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fpt_net_ext.1"> This SFR defines the ability of the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent
        to maintain information about its last successful connection with the environmental <abbr
          linkend="MDM"/> Server (i.e., the last successful invocation of the trusted channel for
        that interface, as defined in FTP_ITC_EXT.1 of the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>). It does not
        need to use any functionality defined in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> to do this, and doing
        this does not prevent the enforcement of any security requirements from the <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/>.</con-mod> -->
    </base-pp>
    
    <base-pp version="3.1" name="Mobile Device Fundamentals" product="Mobile Device" short="MDF"
      url="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=417&amp;id=417">
      <!--       xmlurl="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/commoncriteria/mobile-device/master/input/mobile-device.xml"> -->
      
      
      <modified-sfrs>
        <subsection id="fcs" title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)">
          <f-component id="fcs_ckm_ext.4" name="Cryptographic Key Destruction">
            
            <note role="application"> This SFR exists in the MDF PP and does not need to be modified for this PP-Module. Note
              however that its scope is expanded to include keys and key material that are used by the TSF
              described by this PP-Module. This SFR has not been iterated because it is assumed that the key
              destruction function is at least partially implemented by the underlying platform as opposed to
              the WLAN Client itself. For the purposes of this requirement, it is sufficient for the TOE to invoke
              the correct underlying functions of the host to perform the zeroization—it does not imply that
              the TOE has to include a kernel-mode memory driver to ensure the data are zeroized.
              <h:p/>
              Any security related information (such as keys, authentication data, and passwords) must be
              zeroized when no longer in use to prevent the disclosure or modification of security critical data.
              <h:p/>
              The zeroization indicated above applies to each intermediate storage area for plaintext key or CSP
              (i.e., any storage, such as memory buffers, that is included in the path of such data) upon the
              transfer of the key or CSP to another location.
              <h:p/>
              Additionally, although IEEE 802.11-2016 does not specify PMK lifetimes (described in IEEE
              802.11-2016 Section 11.6.1.3) for WLAN Clients, these lifetimes should be limited, and the
              PMKSA cleared, in such a way as to prevent continued use of the same PMK for more than 24
              hours. Thus, for PMKs, “when no longer needed” is after 24 hours.
            </note>
          </f-component>
          
          
          <f-component id="fcs_cop.1" name="Cryptographic Operation">
            <note role="application">Several iterations of this SFR exist in the MDF PP and do not need to be
              modified for this PP-Module. Note however that their scope is expanded to include cryptographic
              operations that are required by the WLAN Client in order to perform its security functionality.
            </note>
          </f-component>
          
          <f-component id="fcs_rbg_ext.1" name="Random Bit Generation">
            
            <note role="application">This SFR exists in the MDF PP and does not need to be modified for this PP-Module. Note
              however that its scope is expanded to include random bit generation functions that are required
              by the WLAN Client in order to perform its security functionality.
            </note>
          </f-component>
          
          
        </subsection>
      </modified-sfrs>
      <additional-sfrs/>
      
      
      <!-- 
      <con-toe> When this <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> is used to extend the MDF PP, the TOE type for
        the overall TOE is still a mobile device. The TOE boundary is simply extended to include the
          <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent application that runs on the mobile device.</con-toe>
      <con-sec-prob/>
      <con-obj/>
      <con-op-en/>
      <con-mod id="T.BACKUP"> This threat protects user data from unauthorized logical access. An
        attacker would attempt to exploit this threat by first exploiting the T.PHYSICAL, T.FLAWAPP,
        or T.PERSISTENT threats defined in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> against the mobile device
        as a whole, and then using the device itself as an attack vector against any backup data
        stored on the TOE.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="O.ACCOUNTABILITY"> The <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> provides an objective,
        O.INTEGRITY, that ensures that the integrity of the mobile device is maintained. This
        objective assists in the implementation of O.INTEGRITY by providing records of
        administrative activity, which would include actions that could cause the integrity of the
        mobile device to be lost.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="O.APPLY_POLICY"> This objective supports the implementation of the O.CONFIG
        objective defined in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> by specifying an additional method by
        which the TSF may be configured.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="O.DATA_PROTECTION_TRANSIT"> This objective extends the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"
        />’s O.COMMS objective by ensuring that the communications related to <abbr linkend="MDM"/>
        Agent functionality are secured in the same manner as other sensitive data transmitted
        to/from the mobile device.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="O.STORAGE"> This objective extends the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>’s O.STORAGE
        objective by ensuring that the mobile device’s data-at-rest protection mechanisms can also
        be used to secure the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent and related data.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="OE.DATA_PROPER_ADMIN"> This objective extends the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>’s
        OE.CONFIG objective by expecting that TOE administrators act appropriately when installing
        or configuring the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="OE.DATA_PROPER_USER"> This objective extends the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>’s
        OE.NOTIFY and OE.PRECAUTION objectives by setting reasonable expectations for user security
        behavior.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="OE.IT_ENTERPRISE"> This objective helps mitigate the T.EAVESDROP and T.NETWORK
        threats defined by the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> by reducing the network exposure of the
        mobile device. This does not conflict with the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> because the <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/> does not set specific expectations for the level of security that the
        enterprise provides, but all use cases from the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> set expectations
        that the mobile device is used for some enterprise purposes so it is reasonable to expect
        the enterprise have security controls in place to protect these functions. </con-mod>
      <con-mod id="OE.MOBILE_DEVICE_PLATFORM"> This objective is suitable because the <abbr
          linkend="MDM"/> Agent can reasonably expect the device it has been deployed on to be
        secure.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="OE.WIRELESS_NETWORK"> This objective is suitable because while the <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/> does not associate any availability metrics with wireless
        communications, the mobile device will always provide the ability to access a wireless
        network.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fau_alt_ext.2"> This SFR requires the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent to use a
        trusted channel defined by FTP_ITC_EXT.1 in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> to transmit data
        about its own behavior to the Operational Environment.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fau_gen.1(2)"> The <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> defines FAU_GEN.1; this <abbr
          linkend="PP-Module"/> defines a second iteration to use the same audit mechanism to
        generate audit records for the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent’s behavior. It may alternatively
        allow the TSF to generate its own audit trail, which does not impede the MDF from enforcing
        its own security functionality.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fau_sel.1(2)"> The <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> defines FAU_SEL.1; this <abbr
          linkend="PP-Module"/> defines a second iteration to use the same audit mechanism to select
        the auditable events to be generated by the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent. Note that the <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/> does not mandate this requirement so it is possible that only the
          <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent portion of the TOE may implement it. In this case, the SFR
        provides a selection for the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent to implement its own mechanism to
        perform this function rather than a platform-provided one.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fia_enr_ext.2"> This SFR requires the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent to record data
        that it receives from the Operational Environment. It does not need to use any functionality
        defined in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> to do this, and doing this does not prevent the
        enforcement of any security requirements from the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>. </con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fmt_pol_ext.2"> This SFR requires the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent to use a
        digital signature algorithm to validate data that it receives from the Operational
        Environment. To do this, the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent will use the functionality defined
        by the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> in FCS_COP.1(3).</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fmt_smf_ext.4"> This SFR defines the ability of the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent
        to interact with the mobile device to execute the management functions defined by
        FMT_MOF_EXT.1 in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>. The <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> specifically
        indicates in FMT_MOF_EXT.1.2 that some management functions may be performed via
        MDM.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fmt_unr_ext.1"> This SFR defines the functions performed by the <abbr
          linkend="MDM"/> Agent when unenrolled from an <abbr linkend="MDM"/>. The <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/> defines unenrollment actions in FMT_SMF_EXT.2, and goes on to note
        that these actions may be performed “perhaps via an <abbr linkend="MDM"/> agent,” so this is
        expected behavior. </con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fau_stg_ext.3"> This SFR defines the ability of the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent
        to store generated audit data in the audit storage provided by the mobile device. The <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/> defines the capability for audit storage in FAU_STG.1.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="fpt_net_ext.1"> This SFR defines the ability of the <abbr linkend="MDM"/> Agent
        to maintain information about its last successful connection with the environmental <abbr
          linkend="MDM"/> Server (i.e., the last successful invocation of the trusted channel for
        that interface, as defined in FTP_ITC_EXT.1 of the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/>). It does not
        need to use any functionality defined in the <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> to do this, and doing
        this does not prevent the enforcement of any security requirements from the <abbr
          linkend="Base-PP"/>.</con-mod> -->
    </base-pp>
      
    <man-sfrs>
      <subsection id="fau" title="Security Audit (FAU)">
        
        <!-- SME: note that this SFR was updated substantially to be consistent with how auditing is handled in current PP-Modules. -->
        <f-component id="fau_gen.1/wlan" name="Audit Data Generation (Wireless LAN)">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="fau_gen.1.1/wlan">
            <title>The TSF shall <h:b>
              <selectables>
                <selectable>invoke platform-provided functionality</selectable>
                <selectable>implement functionality</selectable>
              </selectables>
            </h:b> to generate an audit record of the following auditable events:
                 <h:ol type="a">
                <h:li>Startup and shutdown of the audit functions;</h:li>
                <h:li>All auditable events for [<h:i>not specified</h:i>] level of audit; and</h:li>
                <h:li>[<h:i>all auditable events specified in the Auditable Events table</h:i>].</h:li>
              </h:ol>
            </title>
            <note role="application">If auditing for the WLAN Client cannot be controlled separately from its underlying platform, 
              the "Startup and shutdown of the audit functions" event defined in each Base-PP is sufficient to address that event for this iteration of the SFR.
              <h:p/>
              The Auditable Events table includes auditable events for SFRs that are not mandatory. If the TOE does not claim a particular non-mandatory SFR, it is not expected to
              generate any corresponding audit records for that SFR. 
              <h:p/>
              The Auditable Events table includes auditable events for FPT_TST_EXT.1/WLAN. If the TOE does not perform its own self-tests (i.e., "TOE platform" is selected in FPT_TST_EXT.1.1/WLAN and FPT_TST_EXT.1.2/WLAN),
              the audit record for this event may also be generated by the TOE platform.
              <h:p/>
              <h:b><ctr id="audit" ctr-type="Table"> Auditable Events</ctr></h:b>
              <h:table style="margin-top:0px;white-space:10px">
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TH>Requirement</h:TH>
                  <h:TH>Auditable Events</h:TH>
                  <h:TH>Additional Audit Record Contents</h:TH>
                </h:TR>
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD>FAU_GEN.1/WLAN</h:TD>
                  <h:TD colspan="2">None.</h:TD>
                </h:TR>
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD>FCS_CKM.1/WLAN</h:TD>
                  <h:TD colspan="2">None.</h:TD>
                </h:TR>                
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD>FCS_CKM.2/WLAN</h:TD>
                  <h:TD colspan="2">None.</h:TD>
                </h:TR>                
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD rowspan="2">FCS_TLSC_EXT.1/WLAN</h:TD>
                  <h:TD>Failure to establish an EAP-TLS session.</h:TD><h:td>Reason for failure.<h:br/><h:br/>Non-TOE endpoint of connection.</h:td></h:TR>
                <h:tr><h:TD>Establishment/termination of an EAP-TLS session.</h:TD><h:td>Non-TOE endpoint of connection.</h:td>
                </h:tr>
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD>FCS_TLSC_EXT.2/WLAN</h:TD>
                  <h:TD colspan="2">None.</h:TD>
                </h:TR>
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD>FIA_PAE_EXT.1</h:TD>
                  <h:TD colspan="2">None.</h:TD>
                </h:TR> 
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD>FIA_X509_EXT.2/WLAN</h:TD>
                  <h:TD colspan="2">None.</h:TD>
                </h:TR>
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD rowspan="2">FIA_X509_EXT.4</h:TD>
                  <h:TD>Attempts to load certificates.</h:TD><h:td>None.</h:td></h:TR>
                  <h:tr><h:TD>Attempts to revoke certificates.</h:TD><h:td>None.</h:td>
                </h:tr> 
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD>FMT_SMF.1/WLAN</h:TD>
                  <h:TD colspan="2">None.</h:TD>
                </h:TR> 
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD rowspan="2">FPT_TST_EXT.1/WLAN</h:TD>
                  <h:TD>Execution of this set of TSF self-tests.</h:TD><h:td>None.</h:td></h:TR>
                <h:tr><h:TD><selectables>
                  <selectable>Detected integrity violation.</selectable>
                  <selectable>None.</selectable>
                </selectables></h:TD>
                  <h:TD><selectables>
                    <selectable>The TSF binary file that caused the integrity violation.</selectable>
                    <selectable>None.</selectable>
                  </selectables></h:TD>
                </h:tr>
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD>FTA_WSE_EXT.1</h:TD>
                  <h:TD>All attempts to connect to access points.</h:TD>
                  <h:TD>Identity of access point being connected to.<h:br/><h:br/>Success and failures (including reason for failure).</h:TD>
                </h:TR>    
                <h:TR>
                  <h:TD>FTP_ITC_EXT.1/WLAN</h:TD>
                  <h:TD>All attempts to establish a trusted channel.</h:TD>
                  <h:TD>Identification of the non-TOE endpoint of the channel.</h:TD>
                </h:TR> 
              </h:table>
              <h:p/>
            </note>            
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="fau_gen.1.2/wlan">
            <title>The <h:b><selectables>
              <selectable>TSF</selectable>
              <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
            </selectables></h:b> shall record within each audit record at
              least the following information: <h:ol type="a">
                <h:li>Date and time of the event, type of event, subject identity, (if relevant) the outcome 
                  (success or failure) of the event; and</h:li>         
                <h:li>For each audit event type, based on the auditable event definitions of the functional components 
                  included in the PP<h:b>-Module</h:b>/ST, [<h:i>Additional Audit Record Conents as specified in Auditable Events table</h:i>].</h:li>
              </h:ol>
            </title>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>
                The evaluator shall check the <abbr linkend="TSS"/> and ensure that it provides a format for audit records. Each audit record format type must be covered, along with a brief description of each field. <h:p/> 
                If "invoke platform-provided functionality" is selected, the evaluator shall examine the <abbr linkend="TSS"/> to verify that it describes (for each supported platform) how this functionality is invoked 
                (it should be noted that this may be through a mechanism that is not implemented by the WLAN Client; nonetheless, that mechanism will be identified in the <abbr linkend="TSS"/> as part of this evaluation activity).<h:p/>  
              </TSS>
              <Guidance>
                The evaluator shall check the operational guidance and ensure that it lists all of the auditable
                events and provides a format for audit records. Each audit record format type must be
                covered, along with a brief description of each field. The evaluator shall check to make sure
                that every audit event type mandated by the PP-Module is described and that the description of the
                fields contains the information required in FAU_GEN.1.2/WLAN, and the additional information
                specified in the Auditable Events table.
                <h:p/>
                The evaluator shall in particular ensure that the operational guidance is clear in relation to the
                contents for failed cryptographic events. In the Auditable Events table, information detailing the cryptographic
                mode of operation and a name or identifier for the object being encrypted is required. The
                evaluator shall ensure that name or identifier is sufficient to allow an administrator reviewing
                the audit log to determine the context of the cryptographic operation (for example,
                performed during a key negotiation exchange, performed when encrypting data for transit) as
                well as the non-TOE endpoint of the connection for cryptographic failures relating to
                communications with other IT systems.
                <h:p/>
                The evaluator shall also make a determination of the administrative actions that are relevant
                in the context of this PP-Module. The TOE may contain functionality that is not evaluated in the
                context of this PP-Module because the functionality is not specified in an SFR. This functionality may
                have administrative aspects that are described in the operational guidance. Since such
                administrative actions will not be performed in an evaluated configuration of the TOE, the
                evaluator shall examine the operational guidance and make a determination of which
                administrative commands, including subcommands, scripts, and configuration files, are related
                to the configuration (including enabling or disabling) of the mechanisms implemented in the
                TOE that are necessary to enforce the requirements specified in the PP-Module, which thus form the
                set of “all administrative actions”. The evaluator may perform this activity as part of the
                activities associated with ensuring the AGD_OPE guidance satisfies the requirements.   
                <h:p/> 
              </Guidance>
              <Tests>
                The evaluator shall test the TOE’s ability to correctly generate audit records by having the TOE
                generate audit records in accordance with the assurance activities associated with the
                functional requirements in this EP. When verifying the test results, the evaluator shall ensure
                the audit records generated during testing match the format specified in the administrative
                guide, and that the fields in each audit record have the proper entries.
                <h:p/>               
                Note that the testing here can be accomplished in conjunction with the testing of the security
                mechanisms directly. For example, testing performed to ensure that the administrative
                guidance provided is correct verifies that AGD_OPE.1 is satisfied and should address the
                invocation of the administrative actions that are needed to verify the audit records are
                generated as expected.                              
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection id="fcs" title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)">
        
        
        The cryptographic requirements are also structured to require the use of the Wi-Fi certification
        requirements for WPA2 enterprise, based on the IEEE 802.11 standard. The Wi-Fi Alliance
        WPA2 Enterprise certification program tests devices for data communications interoperability
        at ISO OSI layers 1 and 2, and mandates the use of the Advanced Encryption Standard (AES)-
        Counter with Cipher Block Chaining (Counter with CBC)-Message Authentication Code (MAC)
        algorithm (known collectively as AES-CCMP) for secure connections. Optionally, AES-GCMP
        (Galois/Counter Mode Protocol) can be used.
        
        <!-- to do: go back and update section numbers for 802.11-2016. -->
        <f-component id="fcs_ckm.1/wlan" name="Cryptographic Key Generation (Symmetric Keys for WPA2 Connections)">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="fcs_ckm.1.1/wlan">
            <title>The TSF shall generate <h:b>symmetric</h:b> cryptographic keys in oaccordance with a specified cryptographic key generation algorithm [<h:i><h:b>PRF-384 and
              <selectables>
                <selectable>PRF-704</selectable>
                <selectable>no other algorithm</selectable>
              </selectables>
              (as defined in IEEE 802.11-2016)</h:b></h:i>] and specified key sizes [<h:i><h:b>128 bits and 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>256 bits</selectable>
                <selectable>no other key sizes</selectable>
              </selectables></h:b></h:i>] <h:b>using a Random Bit Generator as specified in FCS_RBG_EXT.1</h:b>.
            </title>
            <note role="application">The cryptographic key derivation algorithm required by IEEE 802.11-2016
              (Section 11.6.1.2) and verified in WPA2 certification is PRF-384, which uses the HMAC-SHA-1
              function and outputs 384 bits. The use of GCMP was first defined in IEEE 802.11ac-2014 (Section
              11.4.5) but subsequently integrated into 802.11-2016. This protocol requires a KDF based on HMAC-SHA-256 (for 128-bit symmetric keys) or HMAC-SHA384 (for 256-bit symmetric keys). This KDF outputs 704 bits.
              <h:p/>
              This requirement applies only to the keys that are generated/derived for the communications
              between the access point and the client once the client has been authenticated. It refers to the
              derivation of the PTK from the PMK, which is done using a random value generated by the RBG
              specified in this EP, the HMAC function using SHA-1 as specified in this EP, as well as other
              information. This is specified in 802.11-2012 primarily in section 11.6.1.2.
            </note>            
          </f-element>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>
                The evaluator shall verify that the TSS describes how the primitives defined and implemented
                by this PP-Moduleare used by the TOE in establishing and maintaining secure connectivity to the
                wireless clients. The TSS shall also provide a description of the developer’s method(s) of
                assuring that their implementation conforms to the cryptographic standards; this includes not
                only testing done by the developing organization, but also any third-party testing that is
                performed.
                <h:p/>  
              </TSS>
              <Guidance>
                There are no guidance evaluation activities for this component.   
                <h:p/> 
              </Guidance>
              <Tests>
                The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
                <testlist>
                  <test>
                    The evaluator shall configure the access point so the cryptoperiod of the
                    session key is 1 hour. The evaluator shall successfully connect the TOE to the access
                    point and maintain the connection for a length of time that is greater than the
                    configured cryptoperiod. The evaluator shall use a packet capture tool to determine
                    that after the configured cryptoperiod, a re-negotiation is initiated to establish a new
                    session key. Finally, the evaluator shall determine that the renegotiation has been 
                    successful and the client continues communication with the access point.
                  </test>
                  <test>The evaluator shall perform the following test using a packet sniffing tool to
                    collect frames between the TOE and a wireless LAN access point:
                    <h:p/>
                    Step 1: The evaluator shall configure the access point to an unused channel and
                    configure the WLAN sniffer to sniff only on that channel (i.e., lock the sniffer on the
                    selected channel). The sniffer should also be configured to filter on the MAC address
                    of the TOE and/or access point.
                    <h:p/>
                    Step 2: The evaluator shall configure the TOE to communicate with a WLAN access
                    point using IEEE 802.11-2016 and a 256-bit (64 hex values 0-f) pre-shared key. The
                    pre-shared key is only used for testing.
                    <h:p/>
                    Step 3: The evaluator shall start the sniffing tool, initiate a connection between the
                    TOE and the access point, and allow the TOE to authenticate, associate, and
                    successfully complete the 4 way handshake with the client.
                    <h:p/>
                    Step 4: The evaluator shall set a timer for 1 minute, at the end of which the evaluator
                    shall disconnect the TOE from the wireless network and stop the sniffer.
                    <h:p/>
                    Step 5: The evaluator shall identify the 4-way handshake frames (denoted EAPOL-key
                    in Wireshark captures) and derive the PTK from the 4-way handshake frames and preshared key as specified in IEEE 802.11-2016.
                    <h:p/>
                    Step 6: The evaluator shall select the first data frame from the captured packets that
                    was sent between the TOE and access point after the 4-way handshake successfully
                    completed, and without the frame control value 0x4208 (the first 2 bytes are 08 42).
                    The evaluator shall use the PTK to decrypt the data portion of the packet as specified
                    in IEEE 802.11-2012, and shall verify that the decrypted data contains ASCII-readable
                    text.
                    <h:p/>
                    Step 7: The evaluator shall repeat Step 6 for the next 2 data frames between the TOE
                    and access point and without frame control value 0x4208.
                  </test>
                </testlist>                           
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
        </f-component>
        
        <f-component id="fcs_ckm.2/wlan" name="Cryptographic Key Distribution (Group Temporal Key for WLAN)">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="fcs_ckm.2.1/wlan">
            <title>The TSF shall <h:b>decrypt Group Temporal Key</h:b> in accordance with a specified cryptographic key distribution method 
              [<h:i>AES Key Wrap (as defined in RFC 3394) in an EAPOL-Key frame (as defined in IEEE 802.11-2016 for the packet format and timing considerations</h:i>] <h:b>and does not expose the cryptographic keys</h:b>.
            </title>
            <note role="application">This requirement applies to the Group Temporal Key (GTK) that is received by
              the TOE for use in decrypting broadcast and multicast messages from the Access Point to which
              it's connected. 802.11-2016 specifies the format for the transfer as well as the fact that it must be wrapped by the AES Key Wrap method specified in RFC 3394; the TOE must be capable of
              unwrapping such keys.
            </note>            
          </f-element>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS>
              The evaluator shall check the TSS to ensure that it describes how the GTK is unwrapped prior to
              being installed for use on the TOE using the AES implementation specified in this PP-Module.
              <h:p/>  
            </TSS>
            <Guidance>
              There are no guidance evaluation activities for this component.   
              <h:p/> 
            </Guidance>
            <Tests>
              The evaluator shall perform the following test using a packet sniffing tool to collect frames
              between the TOE and a wireless access point (which may be performed in conjunction with the
              assurance activity for FCS_CKM.1.1/WLAN).
              <h:p/> 
              Step 1: The evaluator shall configure the access point to an unused channel and configure the
              WLAN sniffer to sniff only on that channel (i.e., lock the sniffer on the selected channel). The
              sniffer should also be configured to filter on the MAC address of the TOE and/or access point.
              <h:p/> 
              Step 2: The evaluator shall configure the TOE to communicate with the access point using IEEE
              802.11-2016 and a 256-bit (64 hex values 0-f) pre-shared key, setting up the connections as
              described in the operational guidance. The pre-shared key is only used for testing.
              <h:p/> 
              Step 3: The evaluator shall start the sniffing tool, initiate a connection between the TOE and
              access point, and allow the TOE to authenticate, associate, and successfully complete the 4-way
              handshake with the TOE.
              <h:p/> 
              Step 4: The evaluator shall set a timer for 1 minute, at the end of which the evaluator shall
              disconnect the TOE from the access point and stop the sniffer.
              <h:p/> 
              Step 5: The evaluator shall identify the 4-way handshake frames (denoted EAPOL-key in
              Wireshark captures) and derive the PTK and GTK from the 4-way handshake frames and preshared key as specified in IEEE 802.11-2016.
              <h:p/> 
              Step 6: The evaluator shall select the first data frame from the captured packets that was sent
              between the TOE and access point after the 4-way handshake successfully completed, and with
              the frame control value 0x4208 (the first 2 bytes are 08 42). The evaluator shall use the GTK to
              decrypt the data portion of the selected packet as specified in IEEE 802.11-2016, and shall verify
              that the decrypted data contains ASCII-readable text.
              <h:p/> 
              Step 7: The evaluator shall repeat Step 6 for the next 2 data frames with frame control value
              0x4208.
            </Tests>
          </aactivity>
        </f-component>
        
        <!-- SME: the TLS cipher suites in this SFR were out of date compared to recent PPs. Additionally, TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA is not being mandated in PPs anymore. We have updated the cipher suites to be consistent with 
        NDcPP. Please confirm appropriateness. -->
        <f-component id="fcs_tlsc_ext.1/wlan" name="TLS Client Protocol (EAP-TLS for WLAN)">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="fcs_tlsc_ext.1.1/wlan">
            <title>The TSF shall implement TLS 1.2 (RFC 5246) and               
            <selectables>
              <selectable>TLS 1.1 (RFC 4346)</selectable>
              <selectable>no other TLS version</selectable>
            </selectables> in support of the EAP-TLS protocol as specified in RFC 5216 supporting the following cipher suites:
            <selectables linebreak="yes">
                <selectable>TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA as defined in RFC 3268</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA as defined in RFC 3268</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_DHE_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA as defined in RFC 3268</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_DHE_RSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA as defined in RFC 3268</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA as defined in RFC 4492</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_RSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA as defined in RFC 4492</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_ECDSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA as defined in RFC 4492</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_ECDSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA as defined in RFC 4492</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA256 as defined in RFC 5246</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_ SHA256 as defined in RFC 5246</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_DHE_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_ SHA256 as defined in RFC 5246</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_DHE_RSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_ SHA256 as defined in RFC 5246</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_128_GCM_SHA256 as defined in RFC 5288</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_256_GCM_SHA384 as defined in RFC 5288</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_DHE_RSA_WITH_AES_128_GCM_SHA256 as defined in RFC 5288</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_DHE_RSA_WITH_AES_256_GCM_SHA384 as defined in RFC 5288</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_ECDSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA256 as defined in RFC 5289</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_ECDSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA384 as defined in RFC 5289</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_ECDSA_WITH_AES_128_GCM_SHA256 as defined in RFC 5289</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_ECDSA_WITH_AES_256_GCM_SHA384 as defined in RFC 5289</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_RSA_WITH_AES_128_GCM_SHA256 as defined in RFC 5289</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_RSA_WITH_AES_256_GCM_SHA384 as defined in RFC 5289</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA256 as defined in RFC 5289</selectable>
                <selectable>TLS_ECDHE_RSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA384 as defined in RFC 5289</selectable>
            </selectables>.   
            </title>
            <note role="application">If any of the ECDHE cipher suites are selected by the ST author, it is necessary
              to clame the selection-based requirement FCS_TLSC_EXT.2/WLAN.
            </note>            
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="fcs_tlsc_ext.1.2/wlan"><title>The TSF shall generate random values used in the EAP-TLS exchange
            using the RBG specified in FCS_RBG_EXT.1.</title>
          </f-element>  
          <f-element id="fcs_tlsc_ext.1.3/wlan"><title>The TSF shall use X509 v3 certificates as specified in FIA_X509_EXT.1.</title>
          </f-element>    
          <f-element id="fcs_tlsc_ext.1.4/wlan"><title>The TSF shall verify that the server certificate presented includes the
            Server Authentication purpose (id-kp 1 with OID 1.3.6.1.5.5.7.3.1) in the extendedKeyUsage
            field.</title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="fcs_tlsc_ext.1.5/wlan"><title>The TSF shall allow an authorized administrator to configure the list
            of CAs that are allowed to sign authentication server certificates that are accepted by the TOE.</title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="fcs_tlsc_ext.1.6/wlan"><title>The TSF shall allow an authorized administrator to configure the list
            of algorithm suites that may be proposed and accepted during the EAP-TLS exchanges.</title>
          </f-element>
          <note role="application">The cipher suites to be tested in the evaluated configuration are limited by this
            requirement. The ST author should select the optional cipher suites that are supported.
            It is necessary to limit the cipher suites that can be used in an evaluated configuration
            administratively on the server in the test environment.
            <h:p/>
            While FCS_TLSC_EXT.1.4/WLAN requires that the TOE perform certain checks on the certificate
            presented by the authentication server, there are corresponding checks that the authentication
            server will have to perform on the certificate presented by the client; namely that the
            extendedKeyUsage field of the client certificate includes "Client Authentication" and that the
            digital signature bit (for the Diffie-Hellman cipher suites) or the key encipherment bit (for RSA
            cipher suites) be set. Certificates obtained for use by the TOE will have to conform to these
            requirements in order to be used in the enterprise.
            <h:p/>
            The FIA_X509_EXT.1 requirements defined in each of the possible Base-PPs define requirements that
            the underlying platform is expected to implement.
          </note> 
          <aactivity>
            <TSS>
              The evaluator shall check the description of the implementation of this protocol in the TSS to
              ensure that the cipher suites supported are specified. The evaluator shall check the TSS to ensure
              that the cipher suites specified include those listed for this component.
              <h:p/>  
            </TSS>
            <Guidance>
              The evaluator shall check the operational guidance to ensure that it contains instructions on
              configuring the TOE so that TLS conforms to the description in the TSS (for instance, the set of
              cipher suites advertised by the TOE may have to be restricted to meet the requirements).
              <h:p/> 
              The evaluator shall check that the guidance contains instructions for the administrator to
              configure the list of Certificate Authorities that are allowed to sign certificates used by the
              authentication server that will be accepted by the TOE in the EAP-TLS exchange, and instructions
              on how to specify the algorithm suites that will be proposed and accepted by the TOE during the
              EAP-TLS exchange.
              <h:p/> 
            </Guidance>
            <Tests>
              The evaluator shall write, or the TOE developer shall provide, an application for the purposes of
              testing TLS.<h:p/> 
              The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
              <testlist>
                <test>The evaluator shall establish a TLS connection using each of the cipher suites
                  specified by the requirement. This connection may be established as part of the
                  establishment of a higher-level protocol, e.g., as part of an EAP session. It is sufficient to
                  observe the successful negotiation of a cipher suite to satisfy the intent of the test; it is
                  not necessary to examine the characteristics of the encrypted traffic in an attempt to
                  discern the cipher suite being used (for example, that the cryptographic algorithm is 128-bit
                  AES and not 256-bit AES).
                </test>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall attempt to establish the connection using a server with a
                  server certificate that contains the Server Authentication purpose in the
                  extendedKeyUsage field and verify that a connection is established. The evaluator will
                  then verify that the client rejects an otherwise valid server certificate that lacks the
                  Server Authentication purpose in the extendedKeyUsage field and a connection is not
                  established. Ideally, the two certificates should be identical except for the
                  extendedKeyUsage field.
                </test>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall send a server certificate in the TLS connection that does not
                  match the server-selected cipher suite (for example, send a ECDSA certificate while using
                  the TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA cipher suite or send a RSA certificate while using
                  one of the ECDSA cipher suites.) The evaluator shall verify that the TOE disconnects after
                  receiving the server’s Certificate handshake message.
                </test>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall configure the server to select the
                  TLS_NULL_WITH_NULL_NULL cipher suite and verify that the client denies the
                  connection.
                </test>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall perform the following modifications to the traffic:
                  <h:ul>
                    <h:li>Change the TLS version selected by the server in the Server Hello to a nonsupported TLS version (for example 1.5 represented by the two bytes 03 06) and
                      verify that the client rejects the connection.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Modify at least one byte in the server’s nonce in the Server Hello handshake
                      message, and verify that the client rejects the Server Key Exchange handshake
                      message (if using a DHE or ECDHE cipher suite) or that the server denies the
                      client’s Finished handshake message.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Modify the server’s selected cipher suite in the Server Hello handshake message
                      to be a cipher suite not presented in the Client Hello handshake message. The
                      evaluator shall verify that the client rejects the connection after receiving the
                      Server Hello.</h:li>
                    <h:li>[conditional: the TOE supports at least one cipher suite that uses DHE or ECDHE for key exchange]  
                      Modify the signature block in the Server’s Key
                      Exchange handshake message, and verify that the client rejects the
                      connection after receiving the Server Key Exchange message. This test
                      does not apply to cipher suites using RSA key exchange.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Modify a byte in the Server Finished handshake message, and verify
                      that the client sends an Encrypted Message followed by a FIN and
                      ACK message. This is sufficient to deduce that the TOE responded
                      with a Fatal Alert and no further data would be sent.</h:li>
                    <h:li>Send a garbled message from the server after the server has issued the
                      ChangeCipherSpec message and verify that the client denies the connection.</h:li>
                  </h:ul>
                </test>
              </testlist>
            </Tests>
          </aactivity>
        </f-component>
        
 
       </subsection>
      
      <subsection id="fia" title="Identification and Authentication (FIA)">
        
        
        The baseline requirements for the TOE are fairly limited with respect to I&amp;A, since no formal
        administrative or general purpose users are defined. The extent of the I&amp;A required to be
        performed by the TOE relates to the process of becoming connected to the protected network
        through the Wireless Access System. Additionally, some of the requirements that might
        normally be considered part of the I&amp;A process are specified in other sections of this PP-Module,
        particularly those related to cryptographic protocols used for the wireless communications
        (WPA2). This was done to keep requirements on those protocols grouped together for
        understandability as well as for ease of authoring and applying assurance activities. Therefore, 
        the requirements in this section cover the remaining two aspects of the I&amp;A capabilities the
        TOE must support:
        <h:ul>
        <h:li>802.1X-2010 Authentication. The 802.1X-2010 standard (and associated RFCs) specifies
        authentication of a machine for the purposes of accessing a network. This method is
        used as a precursor to wireless operations using the 802.11-2012 standard. While
        802.1X contains requirements for several different parties that participate in 802.1X
        exchanges, the requirements below are targeted at the TOE’s role as a “supplicant” per
        802.1X.</h:li>
        <h:li>Credentials. The protocols and mechanisms specified in this and other sections of the EP
        rely on certificates for use in the EAP-TLS exchange in performing the 802.1X
        authentication.</h:li>
        </h:ul>
        
        <f-component id="fia_pae_ext.1" name="Port Access Entity Authentication">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="fia_pae_ext.1.1">
            <title>The TSF shall conform to IEEE Standard 802.1X for a Port Access Entity (PAE)
              in the “Supplicant” role.
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              This requirement covers the TOE's role as the supplicant in an 802.1X
              authentication exchange. If the exchange is completed successfully, the TOE will derive the PMK
              as a result of the EAP-TLS (or other appropriate EAP exchange) and perform the 4-way
              handshake with the wireless access system (authenticator) to begin 802.11 communications.
              <h:p/>
              As indicated previously, there are at least two communication paths present during the
              exchange; one with the wireless access system and one with the authentication server that uses
              the wireless access system as a relay. The TOE establishes an EAP over LAN (EAPOL) connection
              with the wireless access system as specified in 802.1X-2010. The TOE and authentication server
              establish an EAP-TLS session (RFC 5216).
              <h:p/>
              The point of performing 802.1X authentication is to gain access to the network (assuming the
              authentication was successful and that all 802.11 negotiations are performed successfully); in
              the terminology of 802.1X, this means the TOE will gain access to the "controlled port" maintained 
              by the wireless access system.
            </note>            
          </f-element>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>
                There are no TSS evaluation activities for this component.
                <h:p/>  
              </TSS>
              <Guidance>
                There are no guidance evaluation activities for this component.   
                <h:p/> 
              </Guidance>
              <Tests>
                The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
                <testlist>
                  <test>
                    The evaluator shall demonstrate that the TOE has no access to the test network. 
                    The evaluator shall attempt to authenticate using an invalid client certificate, such that
                    the EAP-TLS negotiation fails. This should result in the TOE still being unable to access
                    the test network.
                  </test>
                  <test>
                    The evaluator shall demonstrate that the TOE has no access to the test network.
                    The evaluator shall attempt to authenticate using an invalid authentication server
                    certificate, such that the EAP-TLS negotiation fails. This should result in the TOE still
                    being unable to access the test network.
                  </test>
                </testlist>                           
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
        </f-component>
        
        <!-- SME: note that both GPOS and MDF PPs define different versions of FIA_X509_EXT.2. This iteration is formatted on the assumption that its original component is defined in MDF
        (because the GPOS version lacks a 2.2). -->
        <f-component id="fia_x509_ext.2/wlan" name="X.509 Certificate Authentication (EAP-TLS for WLAN)">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="fia_x509_ext.2.1/wlan">
            <title>The TSF shall use X.509v3 certificates as defined by RFC 5280 to
              support [<h:i>[authentication for EAP-TLS exchanges]</h:i>].
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              RFC 5280 defines certificate validation and certification path validation
              requirements that must be implemented by the TSF. The FIA_X509_EXT.1 requirements defined
              in each of the supported Base-PPs define requirements that the underlying platform is expected to
              implement in order to support compliance with this RFC.
            </note>            
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="fia_x509_ext.2.2/wlan">
            <title>When the TSF cannot establish a connection to determine the validity of a
              certificate, the TSF shall 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>allow the administrator to choose whether to accept the certificate in these cases</selectable>
                <selectable>allow the user to choose whether to accept the certificate in these cases</selectable>
                <selectable>accept the certificate</selectable> 
                <selectable>not accept the certificate</selectable>
              </selectables>.
            </title>        
          </f-element>            
          <aactivity>
            <TSS>
              The evaluator shall check the TSS to ensure that it describes how the TOE chooses which
              certificates to use, and any necessary instructions in the administrative guidance for configuring
              the operational environment so that the TOE can use the certificates.
              <h:p/>  
              The evaluator shall examine the TSS to confirm that it describes the behavior of the TOE when a
              connection cannot be established during the validity check of a certificate used in establishing a
              trusted channel. The evaluator shall verify that any distinctions between trusted channels are
              described. If the requirement that the administrator is able to specify the default action, then
              the evaluator shall ensure that the operational guidance contains instructions on how this
              configuration action is performed.
              <h:p/>  
            </TSS>
            <Guidance>
              The evaluator shall check the administrative guidance to ensure that it describes how the TOE
              chooses which certificates to use, and any necessary instructions for configuring the operating
              environment so that the TOE can use the certificates.  
              <h:p/> 
            </Guidance>
            <Tests>
              The evaluator shall perform the following test:
              <testlist>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall demonstrate using a valid certificate that requires certificate validation
                  checking to be performed in at least some part by communicating with a non-TOE IT entity. The
                  evaluator shall then manipulate the environment so that the TOE is unable to verify the validity
                  of the certificate, and observe that the action selected in FIA_X509_EXT.2.2 is performed. If the
                  selected action is administrator-configurable, then the evaluator shall follow the operational 
                  guidance to determine that all supported administrator-configurable options behave in their
                  documented manner.
                </test>
              </testlist>                           
            </Tests>
          </aactivity>
        </f-component>
        
        

        
       </subsection>  
      
      
      <subsection id="fmt" title="Security Management (FMT)">
        
        
        <!-- SME: need clarification on what to do with this since it doesn't seem to be totally correct at the moment - notably, section 1 doesn't say anything about a separate management role as claimed here. -->
        As indicated in Section 1, the TOE is not required to maintain a separate management
        role. It is, however, required to provide functionality to configure certain aspects of TOE
        operation that should not be available to the general user population. If the TOE does provide
        some degree of administrative control, then the appropriate optional requirements
        should be claimed in the ST.

        
        <f-component id="fmt_smf.1/wlan" name="Specification of Management Functions (WLAN Client)">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="fmt_smf.1.1/wlan">
            <title>The TSF shall be capable of performing the following management functions: [
            <h:i>
              <h:ul>
              <h:li>configure security policy for each wireless network:
                <h:ul>
                  <h:li><selectables>
                    <selectable>specify the CA(s) from which the TSF will accept WLAN authentication server certificate(s)</selectable>
                    <selectable>specify the FQDN(s) of acceptable WLAN authentication server certificate(s)</selectable>
                  </selectables>,</h:li>
                  <h:li>security type,</h:li>
                  <h:li>authentication protocol,</h:li>
                  <h:li>client credentials to be used for authentication</h:li>
                </h:ul></h:li>
              </h:ul>
              <selectables linebreak="yes">
                <selectable>specify wireless networks (SSIDs) to which the TSF may connect</selectable>
                <selectable>enable/disable certificate revocation list checking</selectable>
                <selectable>disable ad hoc wireless client-to-client connection capability</selectable>
                <selectable>disable wireless network bridging capability (for example, bridging a
                connection between the WLAN and cellular radios on a smartphone so it can function as
                a hotspot)</selectable>
                <selectable>disable roaming capability</selectable>
                <selectable>enable/disable IEEE 802.1X pre-authentication</selectable>
                <selectable>enable/disable and configure PMK caching:<h:ul>
                  <h:li>set the amount of time (in minutes) for which PMK entries are cached,</h:li>
                  <h:li>set the maximum number of PMK entries that can be cached</h:li>
                </h:ul>
                </selectable>                
              </selectables></h:i>].
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              For installation, the WLAN Client relies on the underlying platform to
              authenticate the administrator to the client machine on which the TOE is installed.
              <h:p/>
              For the function configure the cryptoperiod for the established session keys, the unit of measure
              for configuring the cryptoperiod shall be no greater than an hour. For example: units of measure
              in seconds, minutes and hours are acceptable and units of measure in days or greater are not
              acceptable.
            </note>            
          </f-element>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS>
              There are no TSS evaluation activities for this component.
              <h:p/>  
            </TSS>
            <Guidance>
              The evaluator shall check the operational guidance to verify that every management function claimed by the TOE is described there. The evaluator shall also verify
              that these descriptions include the information required to perform the management duties associated with the function.
              <h:p/> 
            </Guidance>
            <Tests>
              The evaluator shall test the TOE’s ability to provide the management functions by configuring the
              TOE and performing the management activities associated with each function claimed in the SFR. 
              <h:p/> 
              Note that this may be accomplished in conjunction with the testing of other
              requirements, such as FCS_TLSC_EXT.1/WLAN and FTA_WSE_EXT.1.                       
            </Tests>
          </aactivity>
        </f-component>      
      </subsection>     
 
      <subsection id="fpt" title="Protection of the TSF (FPT)">
        
        <!-- SME: note that both GPOS and MDF have an FPT_TST_EXT.1 but neither of them correspond directly to this SFR. Unclear whether it should remain an iteration or if it should be renamed. -->
        <f-component id="fpt_tst_ext.1/wlan" name="TSF Cryptographic Functionality Testing (WLAN Client)">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="fpt_tst_ext.1.1/wlan">
            <title>The <selectables>
              <selectable>TOE</selectable>
              <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
            </selectables> shall run a suite of self-tests during initial start-up (on power on) to demonstrate the correct operation of the TSF.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="fpt_tst_ext.1.2/wlan">
            <title>The <selectables>
              <selectable>TOE</selectable>
              <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
            </selectables> shall provide the capability to
              verify the integrity of stored TSF executable code when it is loaded for execution through the
              use of the TSF-provided cryptographic services.
            </title>
            
            <note role="application">
              While the TOE is defined as a software package running on a platform defined by the claimed Base-PP, it
              is still capable of performing the self-test activities required above. However, if the
              cryptographic algorithm implementation is provided by the underlying platform, it may be the
              case where the TSF self-testing is a check to verify that the underlying platform has successfully
              completed its own self-tests prior to the TSF attempting to use the implementation. It should be
              understood that there is a significant dependency on the host platform in assessing the
              assurance provided by these self-tests since a compromise of the underlying platform could
              potentially result in the self-tests functioning incorrectly.
           </note>  
          </f-element>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS>
              The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it details the self tests that are run by the TSF
              on start-up; this description should include an outline of what the tests are actually doing (e.g.,
              rather than saying "memory is tested", a description similar to "memory is tested by writing a
              value to each memory location and reading it back to ensure it is identical to what was written"
              shall be used). The evaluator shall ensure that the TSS makes an argument that the tests are
              sufficient to demonstrate that the TSF is operating correctly.
              <h:p/>
              The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it describes how to verify the integrity of
              stored TSF executable code when it is loaded for execution. The evaluator shall ensure that the
              TSS makes an argument that the tests are sufficient to demonstrate that the integrity of stored
              TSF executable code has not been compromised. The evaluator also ensures that the TSS (or the
              operational guidance) describes the actions that take place for successful (e.g. hash verified) and
              unsuccessful (e.g., hash not verified) cases.
              <h:p/>  
            </TSS>
            <Guidance>
              The evaluator shall ensure that the operational guidance describes the actions that
              take place for successful (e.g. hash verified) and unsuccessful (e.g., hash not verified) cases.
              <h:p/> 
            </Guidance>
            <Tests>
              The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
              <testlist>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall perform the integrity check on a known good TSF executable and
                  verify that the check is successful.
                </test>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall modify the TSF executable, perform the integrity check on the
                  modified TSF executable, and verify that the check fails. 
                </test>
              </testlist>                 
            </Tests>
          </aactivity>
        </f-component>      
      </subsection>   
      

      <subsection id="fta" title="TOE Access (FTA)">
        
        
        <f-component id="fta_wse_ext.1" name="Wireless Network Access">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="fta_wse_ext.1.1">
            <title>The TSF shall be able to attempt connections only to wireless networks
              specified as acceptable networks as configured by the administrator in
              FMT_SMF.1.1/WLAN.
            </title>
            
            <note role="application">
              The intent of this requirement is to allow the administrator to limit the access
              points to which the TOE is allowed to connect. The assignment is used by the ST author to
              specify the attributes (e.g., MAC Address, SSID, certificates, etc.) that can be used by the
              administrator to specify the acceptable access points.
            </note>  
          </f-element>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS>
              The evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine that all of the attributes that can be used to
              specify acceptable networks (access points) are specifically defined.
              <h:p/>  
            </TSS>
            <Guidance>
              The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to determine that it contains guidance for
              configuring each of the attributes identified in the TSS.
              <h:p/> 
            </Guidance>
            <Tests>
              The evaluator shall perform the following tests for each attribute:
              <testlist>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall configure the TOE to allow a connection with a specific access point.
                  The evaluator shall also configure the test environment such that the allowed access point and
                  an access point that is not allowed are both “visible” to the TOE. The evaluator shall
                  demonstrate that they can successfully establish a session with the allowed access point. The
                  evaluator shall then attempt to establish a session with the disallowed access point and
                  observe that the access attempt fails.
                </test>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall configure the TOE to allow a connection with a specific access point
                  using EAP-TLS authentication (not only will the valid SSID be configured, but the TOE will also
                  be provided with certificates to complete the EAP-TLS authentication). The evaluator shall also
                  configure the test environment such that an access point broadcasts the SSID the TOE has
                  been configured to connect to but the authentication server does not have valid credentials.
                  The evaluator shall then attempt to establish a session with the valid SSID/invalid
                  authentication server and observe that the access attempt fails. 
                </test>
              </testlist>                 
            </Tests>
          </aactivity>
        </f-component>      
      </subsection>   
 
 
      <subsection id="ftp" title="Trusted Path/Channels (FTP)">
        
        <!-- SME: this SFR has the same issue that FPT_TST_EXT.1/WLAN has. Specifically, it's shown as an iteration but the Base-PPs each contain their own version of this, and the Module's version if it isn't the same as either one of them.
        So it's not really appropriate to say it's iterated. It may be better just to define this as its own independent component (i.e. FTP_ITC_EXT.2). -->
        <f-component id="ftp_itc_ext.1/wlan" name="Wireless Network Access">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="ftp_itc_ext.1.1/wlan">
            <title>The TSF shall use 802.11-2016, 802.1X, and EAP-TLS to provide a
              trusted communication channel between itself and a wireless access point that is logically
              distinct from other communication channels, provides assured identification of its end points,
              protects channel data from disclosure, and detects modification of the channel data.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="ftp_itc_ext.1.2/wlan">
            <title>The TSF shall initiate communication via the trusted channel for
              wireless access point connections.
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              The intent of the above requirement is to use the cryptographic protocols
              identified in the requirement to protect communications between the TOE and the Access Point.
              <h:p/>
              The requirement implies that not only are communications protected when they are initially
              established, but also on resumption after an outage. It may be the case that some part of the
              TOE setup involves manually setting up tunnels to protect other communication, and if after an
              outage the TOE attempts to re-establish the communication automatically with (the necessary)
              manual intervention, there may be a window created where an attacker might be able to gain
              critical information or compromise a connection. The following tests are only intended to cover
              the WLAN communication channel (not other communication channels that may be available on
              the TOE such as mobile broadband).
            </note>              
          </f-element>

          <aactivity>
            <TSS>
              The evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine that it describes the details of the TOE
              connecting to an access point in terms of the cryptographic protocols specified in the
              requirement, along with TOE-specific options or procedures that might not be reflected in the
              specification. The evaluator shall also confirm that all protocols listed in the TSS are specified and
              included in the requirements in the ST.
              <h:p/>  
            </TSS>
            <Guidance>
              The evaluator shall confirm that the operational guidance includes instructions for establishing
              the connection to the access point and that it includes recovery instructions should a
              connection be unintentionally broken.
              <h:p/> 
            </Guidance>
            <Tests>
              The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
              <testlist>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall ensure that the TOE is able to initiate communications with
                  an access point using the protocols specified in the requirement by setting up the
                  connections as described in the operational guidance and ensuring that communications
                  are successful.
                </test>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall ensure, for each communication channel with an authorized
                  IT entity, the channel data is not sent in plaintext.
                </test>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall ensure, for each communication channel with an authorized
                  IT entity, modification of the channel data is detected by the TOE.
                </test>
                <test>
                  The evaluators shall physically interrupt the connection from the TOE to the
                  access point (e.g., moving the TOE host out of range of the access point, turning the
                  access point off). The evaluators shall ensure that subsequent communications are
                  appropriately protected, at a minimum in the case of any attempts to automatically
                  resume the connection or connect to a new access point.
                </test>
              </testlist>                 
              Further evaluation activities are associated with the specific protocols.
            </Tests>
          </aactivity>
        </f-component>      
      </subsection>  

 
    </man-sfrs>
    
    <opt-sfrs>
      <subsection title="Identification and Authentication (FIA)" id="fia_opt">
        
        <f-component id="fia_x509_ext.4" name="X.509 Certificate Storage and Management">
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="fia_x509_ext.4.1">
            <title>The TSF shall store and protect certificate(s) from unauthorized deletion and
              modification.
            </title>      
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="fia_x509_ext.4.2">
            <title>The TSF shall provide the capability for authorized administrators to load
              X.509v3 certificates into the TOE for use by the TSF.
            </title>        
            <note role="application">
              This SFR may be included if the TOE includes the capability to store and manage certificates. Note that this
              is intended to be used if the certificate storage capability is actually provided by the TOE and not in cases where
              the TSF is relying on a storage mechanism that is part of the underlying platform.
            </note>   
          </f-element>            
          <aactivity>
            <TSS>
              The evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine that it describes all certificate stores
              implemented that contain certificates used to meet the requirements of this PP-Module. This description
              shall contain information pertaining to how certificates are loaded into the store, and how the
              store is protected from unauthorized access.
              <h:p/>  
            </TSS>
            <Guidance>
              The evaluator shall check the administrative guidance to ensure that it describes how to load X.509 certificates into the TOE's certificate store.
              <h:p/> 
            </Guidance>
            <Tests>
              The evaluator shall perform the following test for each TOE function that requires the use of certificates:
              <testlist>
                <test>
                  The evaluator shall demonstrate that using a certificate without a valid certification path
                  results in the function failing. The evaluator shall then load any certificates needed to
                  validate the certificate to be used in the function and demonstrate that the function succeeds.
                  The evaluator then shall delete one of these dependent certificates and show that the function fails.
                </test>
              </testlist>                           
            </Tests>
          </aactivity>
        </f-component>
        
      </subsection>
      
    </opt-sfrs>

    <sel-sfrs>
      
      <subsection id="fcs_sel" title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)">
        <!-- SME: should this also be expanded to include the ffdhe groups from the most recent TLS package?  -->
        <f-component id="fcs_tlsc_ext.2/wlan" name="TLS Client Support for Supported Groups Extension (EAP-TLS for WLAN)" status="sel-based">
          <selection-depends req="fcs_tlsc_ext.1.1/wlan"/>
          <consistency-rationale/>
          <f-element id="fcs_tlsc_ext.2.1/wlan">
            <title>The TSF shall present the Supported Groups extension in the Client Hello with the following NIST curves:
              <selectables>
                <selectable>secp256r1</selectable>
                <selectable>secp384r1</selectable>
                <selectable>secp521r1</selectable>
              </selectables>.
            </title>
            <note role="application">This requirement must be claimed if any cipher suites beginning with 'TLS-ECDHE' are selected in FCS_TLSC_EXT.1.1/WLAN.
              <h:p/>
              This requirement does not limit the elliptic curves the client may propose for authentication and key agreement.  
              Rather, it asks the ST author to define which of the NIST curves from FCS_COP.1(3) (defined in each supported Base-PP) and FCS_CKM.1/WLAN and FCS_CKM.2/WLAN (each defined in this PP-Module).
            </note>            
          </f-element>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS>
              The evaluator shall verify that the TSS describes the Supported Groups extension and
              whether the required behavior is performed by default or may be configured. 
              <h:p/>  
            </TSS>
            <Guidance>
              If the TSS indicates that the Supported Groups extension must be configured to meet
              the requirement, the evaluator shall verify that the operational guidance includes instructions
              for configuration of this extension.
              <h:p/> 
            </Guidance>
            <Tests>
              The evaluator shall perform the following test:
              <testlist>
                <test>The evaluator shall configure the server to perform an ECDHE key exchange
                  message in the TLS connection using a non-supported ECDHE curve (for example, P192) and shall verify that the TSF disconnects after receiving the server’s Key Exchange
                  handshake message.
                </test>
              </testlist>
            </Tests>
          </aactivity>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>
      
    </sel-sfrs>
  </chapter>

  <appendix title="Optional Requirements" id="optional"> As indicated in <secref linkend="ccl"/>,
    the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the TOE are
    contained in the body of this PP. Additionally, there are three other types of requirements
    specified in <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and <appref
      linkend="objective"/>. The first type (in this appendix) are requirements that can be included
    in the <abbr linkend="ST"/>, but are not required in order for a TOE to claim conformance to
    this PP-Module. The second type (in <appref linkend="sel-based"/>) are requirements based on selections
    in the body of the PP-Module: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements in that
    appendix must be included. The third type (in <appref linkend="objective"/> are components that
    are not required in order to conform to this PP-Module, but will be included in the baseline
    requirements in future versions of this PP-Module, so adoption by vendors is encouraged. </appendix>

  <!-- 
       Do NOT put SFRs in this section. All SFR belong up above in SFR section. 
       To make an SFR optional tag it above as status="sel-based" 
  -->
  <appendix title="Selection-Based Requirements" id="sel-based"> As indicated in the introduction to
    this PP-Module, the baseline requirements are contained in the body of this PP-Module. There are additional requirements based on
    selections in the body of the PP-Module: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements
    below will need to be included. 
  
  
  </appendix>

  <!-- 
       Do NOT put SFRs in this section. All SFR belong up above in SFR section. 
       To make an SFR optional tag it above as status="objective" 
  -->
  <appendix title="Objective Requirements" id="objective"> This appendix includes requirements that
    specify security functionality which also addresses threats. The requirements are not currently
    mandated in the body of this PP-Module as they describe security functionality not yet widely available
    in commercial technology. However, these requirements may be included in the ST such that the
    TOE is still conformant to this PP-Module, and it is expected that they be included as soon as
    possible. </appendix>

<!-- SME: entropy appendix was removed since it was not present in the original EP. Is this appropriate or would you prefer we have a stub appendix that states the entropy source(s) used by the TOE are provided by the OS platform
  and this will therefore be covered through evaluation of the TOE against the claimed Base-PP? -->
  
    <bibliography>
      <entry id="bibCC">
        <tag>CC</tag>
        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation - <h:ul>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R5.pdf">Part
                1: Introduction and General Model</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-001, Version 3.1 Revision 5,
              April 2017.</h:li>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R5.pdf">Part
                2: Security Functional Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-002, Version 3.1 Revision 5,
              April 2017.</h:li>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART3V3.1R5.pdf">Part
                3: Security Assurance Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-003, Version 3.1 Revision 5,
              April 2017.</h:li>
          </h:ul></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibCEM">
        <tag>CEM</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CEMV3.1R5.pdf">Common
            Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security - Evaluation Methodology</h:a>,
          CCMB-2012-09-004, Version 3.1, Revision 5, April 2017.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibGPOS">
        <tag>GPOS</tag>
        <description><h:a
          href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/MMO/PP/PP_OS_V4.2.1.pdf">Protection Profile for General Purpose Operating Systems, Version 4.2.1</h:a></description>
      </entry>      
      <entry id="bibMDF">
        <tag>MDF</tag>
        <description><h:a
          href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/MMO/PP/pp_md_v3.1.pdf">Protection Profile for Mobile Device Fundamentals, Version 3.1</h:a></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bib80211">
        <tag>802.11-2016</tag>
        <description><h:a
          href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7786995">802.11-2016 - IEEE Standard for Information technology—Telecommunications and information exchange between systems Local and metropolitan area networks—Specific requirements - 
          Part 11: Wireless LAN Medium Access Control (MAC) and Physical Layer (PHY) Specifications</h:a></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bib8021X">
        <tag>802.11-2016</tag>
        <description><h:a
          href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5409813">802.1X-2010 - IEEE Standard for Local and metropolitan area networks--Port-Based Network Access Control</h:a></description>
      </entry>      
      <entry id="bibRFC3394">
        <tag>RFC 3394</tag>
        <description><h:a
          href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc3394">RFC 3394 - Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) Key Wrap Algorithm</h:a></description>
      </entry>   
      <entry id="bibRFC4346">
        <tag>RFC 4346</tag>
        <description><h:a
          href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4346">RFC 4346 - The Transport Layer Security (TLS) Protocol Version 1.1</h:a></description>
      </entry>       
      <entry id="bibRFC5216">
        <tag>RFC 5216</tag>
        <description><h:a
          href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5216">RFC 5216 - The EAP-TLS Authentication Protocol</h:a></description>
      </entry>         
      <entry id="bibRFC5246">
        <tag>RFC 5246</tag>
        <description><h:a
          href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5246">RFC 5246 - The Transport Layer Security (TLS) Protocol Version 1.2</h:a></description>
      </entry>        
      <entry id="bibRFC5280">
        <tag>RFC 5280</tag>
        <description><h:a
          href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5280">RFC 5280 - Internet X.509 Public Key Infrastructure Certificate and Certificate Revocation List (CRL) Profile</h:a></description>
      </entry>        
    </bibliography>
  

      <acronyms>
      <entry>
        <term>AES</term>
        <description>Advanced Encryption Standard</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>AF</term>
        <description>Authentication Factor</description>
      </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>AS</term>
          <description>Authentication Server</description>
        </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CA</term>
        <description>Certification Authority</description>
      </entry>      
      <entry>
        <term>CBC</term>
        <description>Cipher Block Chaining</description>
      </entry>      
        <entry>
          <term>CC</term>
          <description>Common Criteria</description>
        </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CCMP</term>
        <description>Counter Mode CBC-MAC Protocol</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CCTL</term>
        <description>Common Criteria Test Laboratory</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CM</term>
        <description>Configuration Management</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>COTS</term>
        <description>Commercial Off-The-Shelf</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DRBG</term>
        <description>Deterministic Random Bit Generator</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DoD</term>
        <description>(United States) Department of Defense</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>FIPS</term>
        <description>Federal Information Processing Standards</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>FQDN</term>
        <description>Fully-Qualified Domain Name</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>GCMP</term>
        <description>Galois/Counter Mode Protocol</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>IEEE</term>
        <description>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>IETF</term>
        <description>Iternet Engineering Task Force</description>
      </entry>      
      <entry>
        <term>IT</term>
        <description>Information Technology</description>
      </entry>      
      <entry>
        <term>KDF</term>
        <description>Key Derivation Function</description>
      </entry>       
      <entry>
        <term>LAN</term>
        <description>Local Area Network</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>MAC</term>
        <description>Message Authentication Code (cryptography) or Media Control Address (system property)</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>OSP</term>
        <description>Organizational Security Policy</description>
      </entry>

      <entry>
        <term>PKI</term>
        <description>Public Key Infrastructure</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PMK</term>
        <description>Pairwise Master Key</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PMKSA</term>
        <description>PMK Security Association</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PP</term>
        <description>Protection Profile</description>
      </entry>      
      <entry>
        <term>PTK</term>
        <description>Pairwise Temporal Key</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PUB</term>
        <description>Publication</description>
      </entry>     
      <entry>
        <term>RBG</term>
        <description>Random Bit Generator</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>SAR</term>
        <description>Security Assurance Requirement</description>
      </entry>  
      <entry>
        <term>SFR</term>
        <description>Security Functional Requirement</description>
      </entry>  
      <entry>
        <term>SSID</term>
        <description>Service Set Identifier</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ST</term>
        <description>Security Target</description>
      </entry>        
      <entry>
        <term>TOE</term>
        <description>Target of Evaluation</description>
      </entry>      
      <entry>
        <term>TSF</term>
        <description>TOE Security Function</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>TSS</term>
        <description>TOE Summary Specification</description>
      </entry>      
      <entry>
        <term>WLAN</term>
        <description>Wireless Local Area Network</description>
      </entry>      

    </acronyms>
  
</Module>

